A homespun murder story.
Fargo is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Joel Coen.
Jerry, a small-town Minnesota car salesman is bursting at the seams with debt...
but he's got a plan.
He's going to hire two thugs to kidnap his wife in a scheme to
collect a hefty ransom from his wealthy father-in-law.
It's going to be a snap and nobody's going to get hurt...
until people start dying.
Enter Police Chief Marge, a coffee-drinking, parka-wearing - and extremely
pregnant - investigator who'll stop at nothing to get her man.
And if you think her small-time investigative skills will
give the crooks a run for their ransom...
you betcha!
Marge Gunderson, played by Frances McDormand.
Jerry Lundegaard, played by William H. Macy.
Carl Showalter, played by Steve Buscemi.
Gaear Grimsrud, played by Peter Stormare.
Wade Gustafson, played by Harve Presnell.
Norm Gunderson, played by John Carroll Lynch.
Fargo is a 1996 black comedy and crime drama film written,
directed, produced and edited by Joel and Ethan Coen.
It stars Frances McDormand, William H.
Macy, Steve Buscemi, Harve Presnell, and Peter Stormare.
McDormand plays police chief Marge Gunderson, who investigates after a car salesman, Jerry Lundegaard (Macy),
hires two dimwitted criminals to kidnap his wife to extort a ransom from her wealthy father.
Filmed in the United States in late 1995, Fargo premiered at the 1996
Cannes Film Festival, where it competed for the Palme d'Or.
Joel Coen won the festival's Prix De La Mise En Scène (Best Director Award).
The film was a critical and commercial success, earning particular acclaim for the Coens'
direction and script and the performances of McDormand, Macy and Buscemi.
Fargo received seven Oscar nominations at the 69th Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best
Supporting Actor for Macy, winning two: Best Actress for McDormand and Best Original Screenplay for the Coens.
In 1998, the American Film Institute named Fargo one of the 100 greatest American films,
the most recent film on the list at point, but it was delisted in 2007.
In 2006, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
An FX television series based on the film, Fargo, premiered in 2014.
The film explores themes of salesclerk, unsociability, police, cheating, ransom.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.